# Shiril Yugdhar Pathak (1) Featured

Software Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Software Coding, Software Design, Core J2SE, Advanced J2EE, Hibernate, Spring, Maven, Apache Tomcat, Eclipse, WebServices, JSP, Servlet, JDBC, JSON, XML, SVN, AWS



Current Designation: Software Developer(Analyst) Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: TIAA Global Business Service (India) Pvt. Notice Period: 3 Months

I td. Highest Degree: Post Graduate Diploma [Advanced

Current Location: Pune Computing]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Pref. Location: Pune, Mumbai, Bengaluru / Bangalore

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: Banking/Financial Services/Broking

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Development, Requirement Gathering, Software Design, Core J2SE, Advanced

J2EE, Hibernate, Spring, Maven, Apache Tomcat, Eclipse, WebServices, JSP, Servlet, JDBC, JSON, XML, SVN, Spring

Boot, Microservices, cloud, AWS, Openshift, SQL, Redis, Oracle

Verified: Phone Number 1 Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

### Summary

Highly motivated professional with 5 years of experience as Software Developer which includes skill set of development with Java

including spring and hibernate framework, worked on OpenShift migration and AWS. Quick learner and excellent team player with strong leadership skills, having ability to meet tight deadlines and work under pressure. Decent communication, interpersonal and analytical skills with abilities in resolving complex issues.

# Work Experience

#### TIAA Global Business Service (India) Pvt. Ltd. as Software Developer(Analyst)

Sep 2018 to Till Date

Client Name TIAA Software Developer

Java (J2EE, Hibernate, Gradle, Spring), Oracle, AWS Technical Environment

Description This application is a backend for retirement related advice for the U.S. participants for their existing plans with the company.

#### Reliance Jio Infocomm Limited as Software Developer(Assistant Manager)

Mar 2016 to Sep 2018

Jio Payment Bank(UPI) Client Name MyJio

Role Software Developer

Java (J2EE-JSP, Servlet, Hibernate, Spring), Oracle

This application is a backend for UPI related services for Jio Payment Bank in MyJio Application using Description J2SE/J2EE, Hibernate and Spring.

Client Name MyJio Software Developer

Java (J2EE-JSP, Servlet, Hibernate, Maven, Spring), Oracle , Redis Technical Environment This application is a backend For MyJio Android Application providing web services and Web related modules using J2SE/J2EE, Hibernate, Spring and Maven.

JPG (Jio Payment Gateway)

MyJio

Software Developer

Java (J2EE-JSP, Servlet, Hibernate, Spring), Oracle , Redis

This Web Application handles the recharge flow by running into the web View of MyJio Android Application after user selects a plan for recharge by integrating various modes of payments like PayTm, JioMoney, Net banking, etc. after selection of a Data/Voice Plan By Customer.

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Pune University in 2015

PG: Post Graduate Diploma (Advanced Computing) from Centre for Development of Advanced Computing (CDAC) in 2016

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Java

Problem Solver

Amazon Web Services Developer - Associate

#### **IT Skills**

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Core (J2SE) and Advanced (J2EE) JAVA			5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Hibernate (ORM Tool), Spring			5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
AWS, OpenShift			
Sql/PI-sql oracle 11g		2018	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
WEBSERVICES		2017	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
quartz scheduler		2017	0 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
MAVEN		2017	1 Year(s)
WebLogic		2018	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Redis		2018	2 Year(s)
Tortoise SVN		2018	2 Year(s) 4 Month(s)
REST/SOAP, JSP, Servlet, JDBC		2018	2 Year(s) 4 Month(s)
JSON, XML		2020	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Eclipse		2018	2 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
WINDOWS, LINUX		2018	2 Year(s) 4 Month(s)
WEBSERVICES, REST/SOAP			
jsp, servlet, jdbc,			
JSON, XML			

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak	

Marathi	Proficient
Hindi	Expert
English	Expert

### **Projects**

Project Title: AdviceExpress

Client: Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association of America

Duration: Sep 2018 - Till Date Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: Pune Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 4

Project Details: AdviceExpress, Client Name: TIAA, Role: Software Developer Technical Environment: Java (Spring), Oracle, Redis Description; This application is a backend for retirement related advice for the U.S. participants for their existing plans

with the company.

Project Title: Jio payment Bank(UPI)

Client: MyJio Application

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Aug 2017 - Jul 2018 Role: Programmer Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Team Size: 4

Project Details: This application is a backend for UPI related Web-Services for Jio Payment Bank in MyJio Application using

J2SE/J2EE, Hibernate and Spring.

Project Title: Jio Payment Gateway(JPG)

Client: MyJio

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Mar 2017 - Aug 2017 Project Location: RCP ghansoli Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 25 Skill Used: Java (J2EE-JSP, Servlet, Hibernate, Maven, Spring), Oracle, Redis

Role Description: Developer

Project Details: This Web Application handles the recharge flow by running into the web View of MyJio Android Application after user selects a plan for recharge by integrating various modes of payments like PayTm, JioMoney, Net banking, etc. after selection of a Data/Voice Plan By Customer

Project Title: MappCore

Client: MyJio

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: May 2016 - Till Date Project Location: RCP ghansoli Onsite / Offsite: Onsite Role: Programmer Team Size: 25

Skill Used: Java (J2EE-JSP, Servlet, Hibernate, Maven, Spring), Oracle, Redis

Role Description: Developer

Project Details: This application is a backend For MyJio Android Application providing web services and Web related

modules using J2SE/J2EE, Hibernate, Spring, and Maven.

Project Title: API Tester

Client: Jio

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jul 2015 - Sep 2015 Project Location: RCP -ghansoli Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Team Size: 4 Role: Programmer

Skill Used: Java (J2EE- Servlet, JDBC), Oracle

Role Description: Developer

Project Details: A Web application to Test webservices by consuming them and sending Json request and displaying Json

response.

#### **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Category: General Countries: India

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time